《越狱》前情回顾
previously on prison break
嘿  我们上路了
Hey,yo,we're headed out man.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
希望你可以找回你女朋友
I hope you find the girl,buddy.
亲爱的 出什么事了?
Baby,what the hell is going on?
赫克托说你不能假释
Yeah,well Hector says that you can serve your full sentence.
你来这干什么? 玛丽克鲁兹在哪?
What are you doing here,where's Maricruz?
她现在是我的女人了
She's with me now.
我听说你马上能回家了?
What's this I hear about you coming home soon?
你可别再让女儿失望了
You're not getting your daughter's hopes up are you?
你坐稳了吗?
You sitting down?
这周我就能回家了
Your man is coming home this week.
我们可以从这里步行去法院
e can make it to the courthouse on foot from here.
你不明白 所有的东西都在里面
You don't understand,everything is in that car.
我戒毒已经18个月了
I've been clean for 18 months now.
我想用自己的亲身经历
I want to help people get
帮助那些失足朋友从迷失中回来
from where I've been to where I am.
没错
You were right.
我不该把你也卷进来
I should never have gotten you involved in this.
我只是想知道迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
I just need to know what Michael Scofield
帮你拿绿卡的条件是什么
wanted from you in exchange for the green card.
卡罗琳 我干这行已经15年了
Caroline,I've been doing this for 15 years
所有的事情都是为了你
and it's never been about anything other than you,
为了你的家庭 最重要的是为了这个国家
your family and,most importantly,this country.
我需要知道我在为谁卖命
Now,I need to know who I'm working for here.
你在为我效力
You are working for me.
你是否知道任何有关
Are you aware of any arrangement
贝利克警官和罪犯之间
Officer Bellick had
关于监狱工厂工作安排的内幕?
with any inmate regarding Prison Industries?
是的 他把这个权利卖给了约翰 阿布鲁奇
Yeah,he sold it to John Abruzzi.
布拉德 贝利克
Officer Brad Bellick,
辞退原职 立即生效
you're terminated,  effective immediately.
电视台刚刚宣布了悬赏
They just announced the rewards on the TV.
有多少?
How much?
每个悬赏10万美元
$100,000 a piece.
钱就埋在犹他
The money is just outside of Tooele,Utah.
上卡车!
Truck!
派人去这附近所有的医院
Get men in all the area hospitals.
不管他们在哪里 有一个伤得很重
Wherever they are,one of them is bleeding good.
我们必须继续跑
We got to move.
我不行了
I can't.
费尽心思实施越狱计划
You put in all that work,break out of prison,
却没想在这阴沟翻船
only to end up dead at the bottom of a ditch.
听上去有点伤悲
Kind of sad really.
出事的是谁?
So which one of them was it?
十二小时前
每个诊所都派人手监控了
We've got a blanket on all the hospitals.
免费小诊所呢?
Free clinics?
只要是有创可贴和消毒剂的
If they've got Band-Aids and Bactine,
我们都派人去了
we've got a body in there.
只要那两兄弟来医治
The brothers come in for medical,
就会被押送回福克斯河
they're getting it in a van on the way back to Fox River.
另外六个有突破吗?
Anything break on the other six?
已经监控他们的家庭了
Eyes and ears on the families.
目前还没有 或许都躲起来了
So far,no hits. Maybe just laying low.
对罪犯而言什么事情最难办到?
What's the hardest thing in the world for a con to do?
没有吧?
Nothing?
生命中有些事是注定的 你是？
Few things in life are certain,Ms....?
-我姓兰 -死亡 税收
Lang. Death,taxes
事实上逃犯很容易......
and the fact that a man on the run
......在最初的72小时内犯错误
will make a mistake sometime in the first 72 hours.
需要赶路 他会去偷车
Needing distance,he'll steal a car.
需要钱 他会去抢劫
Needing money,he'll rob a store.
需要帮助 他会去信任不该相信之人
Needing help,he'll trust someone that he shouldn't.
一旦他这么做
And when he does...
就会留下蛛丝马迹助我们顺藤摸瓜
he will leave behind the crumbs that will take us right to him.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
迈克尔你在干吗?
Michael,what are you doing?
-辣椒粉  -什么?
Cayenne pepper. What?
厨房里有吗?
In your kitchen,do you have any?
呃...或许有吧
Um... yeah,maybe.
我需要些外用酒精、毛巾
I'm gonna need some rubbing alcohol,some towels
还有止痛药 有用的都拿来
and pain killers,whatever you got.
再来点酒
Some booze.
拜托!
Please!
别紧张 放松
Easy,easy,easy,easy.
我没事  我们走吧
It's fine,man,let's just keep moving.
我们继续跑 血就止不住
We keep moving and that leg keeps bleeding.
血如果止不住
The leg keeps bleeding
我们根本逃不出伊利诺斯州
and we're not getting out of Illinois.
会很疼
This is going to hurt.
很好 忍一下
That's good,that's good,that's good.
这样能封住毛细血管
This will seal the capillaries.
迈克尔  你不该来这里
Michael,you should not have come here.
警察来这问过话了
The police have been here asking questions.
我们别无选择
We didn't have a choice.
听着
Listen,you know I'm thankful
我很感激你帮我获得绿卡
for the help with the green card,
但是我不想卷进来
but I just don't want to get involved. I know,I know it wasn't part
我知道这不是我们原来说好的
of our deal,I know,I know. Yes.
抱歉 真的很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
但我们没其它地方可去
But there was nowhere else to go.
我看到新闻的时候很担心
When I saw you on the news,I was worried.
我真希望你现在已经越过国境
I just hoped you crossed the border by now.
我也是
So did I.
不停的给他上药
Keep giving him these.
看看能否帮他弄身干净衣服
See if you can find him some clean clothes.
好
Okay.
我必须回去把车弄回来
I got to go back and get our car.
别管那车了
Forget the car.
另外搞一辆就是了
We can get another.
我需要的不是一辆车而是我们那辆车
I don't need a car,I need that car.
为什么?
Why?
所有可以帮我们销声匿迹 的东西都在那辆车上
Because in that car is everything we need to disappear.
有什么新发现?
What have you got?
是这么回事
Here we go boss,one of the blues
有个兄弟几小时前抓了个流浪汉
hauled in a vagrant a couple hours ago.
这几件东西似乎都不属于他
Seems the man was in possession of an item or two that didn't exactly belong to him.
看来我们已经逮到第一个错误了
Looks like we got our first mistake.
嘿 有没有日式牛肉干?
Hey,you got any of that oriental jerky?
什么?
Excuse me?
红烧味的
Teriyaki flavor.
没有
No.
仓库里有没有?
You got any in the back?
呃 我看看
Uh,let me check.
伙计 顺便再给我弄瓶老酒
And,uh,give me a bottle of that Early Times while you're back there,junior.
今天给你赚到了
Feel free to earn your paycheck today.
看好店 我马上回来
Watch the store,I'll be right back.
最近怎么样 罗伊?
How goes it,Roy?
实话告诉你
To be honest,Roy,I could've done
我用一根手指就可以搞定你
without the knee to the junk.
你居然咬我 布拉德
You bit me,Brad.
就像个小姑娘似的
Like a little girl,you bite me.
这是你自找的
Well,you had it coming.
或许吧
Yeah,probably did.
我们竟然为这种事打架
You know it's crazy,us taking it out
听上去真的很疯狂
on each other for how things turned out.
要怪的话  就该怪那些犯人
You want someone to blame,how about those convicts
每天起来看到的都是他们的报道
staring up at us from the papers every morning.
他们害我丢了工作
They took my job,
我的养老金、尊严都没了
my pension,my dignity.
当他们翻过那堵墙的时候
When they went over that wall,
他们把一切都带走了
they took all of it right along with them.
带走了我奋斗了一辈子的东西
Everything I worked  for my whole life.
看到悬赏了吗?
See that reward they got?
这帮混蛋死了都比我们活着值钱
Those ass-hats are worth more dead than you and I are alive.
不用多久了
Not for long.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
我是说有人会得到这笔悬赏 好比是我
I mean somebody's going to get that money,might as well be me.
像那样的抓捕工作
You know a job like that
如果多个帮手会更容易些
might go a little smoother with an extra pair of hands.
你真认为我会和你分享那笔赏金?
You really think I'm going to split that reward with you?
当你遇到他们的时候
I'm just saying,you run into those brothers,
双拳难敌四手
two of them,one of you.
到时候你就知道有帮手的好处了
You might find yourself wishing for a good wingman.
快去搞定它 麦克
Just get it done,Mike.
你好
How are you doing?
有事吗?
May I help you?
是的 恰克
Yeah,I hope so,Chuck.
我想你们可能拖走了我的车
I think you may have towed my car.
什么样的车?
What did it look like?
就是你偷背包的车
The car you stole the backpack from.
什么样的车?
What did it look like?
我记不清了 或许是灰色的吧
I don't know,man,maybe it was gray.
灰色的雅阁
It's a gray Accord.
车牌号?
License number?
我就知道这些了
Look,man,that's all I know.
我不是去偷车的
I wasn't after the car.
我还以为包里会有些衣服
Thought the bag had some clothes in it.
还记得车停在哪吗?
You remember where The car was parked?
你停哪的?
Where'd you park it?
汉考克大街和十五大道的拐角
Corner of Hancock and 15th.
我不知道 或许在十五大道附近吧
I don't know,maybe around 15th somewhere,
但是现在肯定不在那了
but it ain't going to be there anymore.
-此话怎讲?  -那就是为什么我没有机会
What do you mean? That's the reason I didn't get
再弄些其他的东西
to grab anything else.
被拖车拖走了
Tow truck rolls up.
已经在查了
Already on it.
60块拖车费
It's going to be 60 bucks for the tow,
24块过夜费
and 24 for the overnight.
好了 我去把你的车开来
All right,be right back with your vehicle.
再等几分钟
Shouldn't take but a few minutes.
喂
Hello?
佩特 是我苏克雷
Petey,it's Sucre.
是费尔南多 苏克雷吗?
As in,Fernando Sucre?
-难道还会有别的?  -但愿没有
Is there another one? Man,I hope not.
但是我的兄弟苏克雷不会给我打电话
But my boy Sucre would not be calling me on the telephone,
他知道这会让我成为他潜逃的从犯
thereby making me an accessory to his dumb-ass escape,man.
我很抱歉 我只是...
I-I'm sorry,bro,I just...
我只是希望你帮我联系玛丽克鲁兹
I just... I just need you to get a hold of Maricruz.
我不能给她打电话
I can't call her cell
因为探员肯定监听的
because the Feds will be all over the place...
听着
Homie,listen,man,
忘了那女孩吧
you have got to forget about that girl.
如果我能忘了她
If I could forget about her,pendejo,
我就会在监狱里
I'd still be at Fox River,
老老实实把刑服完
sitting in cell 40 on your old bunk.
我希望你站稳了
Yeah,well,I hope you're holding on
我有个坏消息
to something tight 'cause I'm about to break it down for you,brother.
她要和赫克托结婚了
She's getting married to Hector
就在星期六
on Saturday.
今天星期几?
What day is today?
周四
Thursday,bro.
很遗憾
Sorry,man.
不管了 今晚你务必把她带到你家
All right,you got to get her to your place tonight.
等等...
Hang on,man...
我只有最后一次机会改变她的决定了
I got one last shot to make her change her mind,dude.
帮我找到她 好不好?
Just find a way to get her there,okay?
等等...苏克雷 别挂
Wait...
关于这个 呃...
About the,uh...
这个打破的窗
about the broken window.
我们在那墙上贴有免责声明
Yeah,we got a disclaimer posted right there on the wall,says we're not responsible...
我不在乎... 不在乎...
Yeah,I don't... I don't... I don't care
我不在乎窗户
about the broken window,Chuck.
我里面有个背包不见了
I had a backpack inside.
拖来的时候就没了
Not when we got it.
还要麻烦你填几张表
I got some paperwork for you to fill out.
你看上去很眼熟
You look familiar.
我刚来的时候你在这里当医生
Yeah,you... you were the attending when I first started here.
原来如此
Sure.
能帮我叫辆出租车吗?
Um,would one of you mind calling me a cab,please?
我看不必了
I don't think so.
唐克雷蒂医生
Look,Dr. Tancredi,I...
祝你好运
I just want to say good luck.
莎拉 唐克雷蒂?
Sara Tancredi?
很抱歉 你有权保持沉默
I'm sorry. You have the right to remain silent.
请把手放在后面
Please place your hands behind your back.
如果你有任何疑问 我愿意去...
If you have any questions,I'm happy to come down to...
唐克雷蒂  出于对你父亲的尊重
Ms. Tancredi,out of respect for your father,
我再说一次 手放后面
I'm going to ask you again.
我父亲?
My father?
我相信他不希望把事情闹大
I'm sure he'd prefer that this went without incident.
在回答警察问题前
You have the right to speak to an attorney
你有权先和律师沟通
before you speak to the police.
你所说的一切可能会成为呈堂证供
Anything you say may be used against you in a court of law.
审讯期间可以要求律师在场
And to have an attorney present during questioning now or in the future.
卡罗琳  警察把她带走了
Caroline,they're taking her in.
当然  我会盯住她的
Of course. I'll keep an eye on her.
在下面签个名...
All you got to do is sign here at the bottom...
然后就能走了
and be on your way.
不好意思
Excuse me,please.
布鲁斯特拖车行
Brewster's Towing.
我是FBI的探员马宏
This is Agent Mahone with the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
你怎么称呼?
Who am I speaking with?
恰克
Chuck.
好的 恰克  请你留意一个可能的情形
Okay,Chuck,I want to alert you to a possible situation.
你在听我说吗 恰克?
Are you listening to me,Chuck?
可能会有人去你那里找一辆车
An individual may be coming there to inquire about a vehicle.
一辆灰色雅阁车 或许车窗还砸碎了
A gray Accord,probably with a busted rear window.
有没有人来找我说的那辆车?
Has anyone come by looking for a vehicle that matches that description?
是的 老板
Yes,sir.
什么时候?
When?
呃...
Uh...
恰克
Chuck.
你告诉我 他什么时候来的?
Will you tell me when he was there?
就是现在
Right now.
斯科菲尔德就在那个拖车行
Brewster's towing.Scofield's there.
恰克拖住他
Chuck,stall him.
我们已派人手过来了 不要让他跑了
We've got people on the way-- do not let him leave.
不要让他跑了
Do not let him leave.
是我的老板 他...
It's my supervisor,he's,he...
我得等有了许可才能放行
I just got to get clearance before,I can release the car.
恰克还在吗? 嘿 恰克
Chuck,you there? Hey,Chuck.
恰克还在吗?
Okay,come on,come on,Chuck,you still with me?
在 等你到了那辆车或许已不在了
Yeah,that vehicle might not be here when you get here.
你得现在就派人过来
You need to send somebody now.
不要让他跑了!
Do not let him leave!
哦！ 他拿走了钥匙
Oh,he got the keys.
那帮警察都在哪儿?!
Where the hell are those units?!
还要6、7分钟才能到
Still six or seven minutes out,sir.
监听设备监控到富兰克林
We got chatter; it's Franklin.
他在打公用电话
He's at a payphone Downtown.
第二个错误了
Mistake number two.
听着 我明白
Look,I know.
亲爱的 我都明白 听我解释好不好?
I know,baby,just let me explain,all right?
你真的当过兵吗?
Were you ever even in the military?
我为国卖命 可是国家却辜负我
I served my country,and my country served me up.
行了吗?
All right?
我也希望现在就能把一切都告诉你
Now,look,I wish I could lay this all out for you right here,right now.
但是亲爱的 真的很抱歉
But just know,baby,I am sorry,
我爱你 等时机成熟
and I love you,and when the time comes,
我会把一切都告诉你
I will explain everything.
给我个不举报你的理由
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't turn you in right now.
你知道吗? 我可以给你三个
You know what? I'll give you three.
我 你
Me,you,
还有可爱的女儿
and that beautiful little girl... who used to love me.
我有个计划
I got a plan.
I got a plan
我先去弄些钱
that is going to get us some money,
然后我们去一个
where you and I and our baby--
再也没有人会找到我们的地方
nobody can ever find us or bother us again.
你得相信我
You got to trust me.
我现在需要你听我把话说完
That's all I need is the opportunity for you to hear me out.
好吗?
All right?
好吧
All right.
那好 听着
All right,listen.
有人试着从你那
Has anybody tried to contact you
打听我的消息吗?
about me?
没有
No.
好
Okay.
好  很好
Okay,that's good,that's good.
听着
Listen.
在“彩虹轩”
In the Rainbow Room...
纽约的一个餐厅
Restaurant,New York City.
你还记得那个地方吗?
Do you remember that beautiful spot
我们拍照片的地方
where we took that picture?
窗户旁边的那张
The one by the window?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
一周后的今天我会在那儿等着
I am going a be waiting in that spot one week from now.
我现在唯一的心愿就是
And that's all that I want in this whole world
我最爱的两个女人能在那等我
is for my two girls to be waiting there for me.
你明白我在说些什么吗?
Do you understand what I'm saying?
我要挂了
Look,I got to go.
宝贝 我只想知道你会不会去?
Baby,I just want to know,are you going to be there?
我不知道
I don't know.
可你是了解我的啊
But you know me.
--是吗?  --是的!
Do I? Yes!
再见 迈尔斯
Good-bye,Miles.
我会通知曼哈顿当局布控
I'll alert the field office in Manhattan
把富兰克林的照片传过去
have them send Franklin's picture
发给彩虹轩的每个职工
to every employee at the Rainbow Room.
接着你就去找他老婆 女人跟女人谈话好办事
Then go have a chat with his wife,woman-to-woman.
问她为什么从未去过福克斯河 探视他丈夫
Ask her why she never once visited her husband at Fox River.
记得装做你什么也不知道的样子
Pretend you don't know the answer.
这段感情很脆弱
That relationship is fragile.
我们不断旁敲侧击 攻破她的心理防线
We keep tapping on cracks,and she's going to break.
好的  长官 我很佩服你的方案
Yes,sir,I appreciate the assignment. I...
我不需要恭维话
Lang,I don't need gratitude.
我只要线索 答案和进展
I need leads,answers,progress.
做不到的话就给我卷铺盖走人
Anybody that can't deliver that just don't even unpack.
-明白吗? -是 长官
Clear? Yes,sir.
惠勒先生
Mr. Wheeler.
稍等别挂
Stand by.
盯紧斯科菲尔德
Stay on Scofield.
我要那辆雅阁车的车牌号
I want the license plate number on that Accord
别再抱着电话不放
and I want you to get it out on the wire.
好
Yeah.
快！
Now.
回头再说
I'll call you back.
怎么了?
What's going on?
显然还有其他人也在找这辆车
Apparently,I wasn't the only one looking for this car.
是啊
Right.
我们走吧
很抱歉 把你也扯进来
I'm sorry I had to involve you in this.
我是说 让你越陷越深
I mean,any more than I already have
好运
Good luck.
你也是
To you,too.
那么...
So,um...
再见了
I'll see you.
但愿还能再见面
Yeah,I hope so.
你还好吗?
You all right?
是的
Yeah.
那就好
Good.
我们向西走 去拿钱 去救LJ
We're heading west,toward the money,toward LJ.
在这之前还有一件事
We just got one more stop to make.
什么事?
What for?
你相信我吗?
You trust me?
我当然相信你 布拉德
Of course I trust you,Brad.
不过要是被人知道的话 我...
It's just that if anybody finds out about this,I...
没人会知道的
They won't.
交给我了
Let me handle this.
大胖子 死胖子 爬上一堵墙
Humpty Dumpty climbed up a wall.
大胖子 死胖子 重重摔下来
Humpty Dumpty had a great fall.
听着
Look...
我已经告诉过联邦探员 我什么都不知道了
I already told the feds I don't know anything,okay?
他们衣冠楚楚 文质彬彬
Those suits with pedicures and penny loafers.
你当然不会说
Why would you?
他们循规蹈矩
They have rules to follow,codes of conduct.
他们要保住饭碗
They got jobs to protect.
而我不一样
Now me,on the other hand.
拜托老大
Come on,Boss.
我发誓
I swear.
这群家伙没让我参与计划
Those guys didn't let me in on any plans.
那你是说 你们每次开会
Then you're telling me in all your little powwows in the yard
他们都没说过
they never once mentioned what they were going to do
逃出去以后有什么打算吗?
once they went over that wall?
没错
That's right.
现在...
Now...
我已经不在这里上班了 大胖子
I may not work here anymore,Big-uns,
但我在这里还是有些影响力的
but I still got influence with people who do,
我说什么他们就会照做
people who will do whatever I ask them to
要他们整谁他们就去整谁
to whoever I ask them to.
还有...
And a...
像你这样凹凸有致的身材
well,let's just say there's some filthy individuals
这么说吧  牢里有些变态
who might enjoy a cellie
最喜欢你这种有女人味的了
with womanly attributes.
把你知道的都说出来
Now,you're going to tell me everything you know
告诉我 他们要去哪
about where those convicts are headed,
否则我就把你扔去喂色狼
or I'm going to throw your fat ass to the wolves.
好 谢谢
Okay,thanks.
第3个错误  有人报告说看到一个
Mistake number three: someone reported seeing
貌似费尔南多 苏克雷的人偷了辆车
a man matching Fernando Sucre's description stealing a car.
在哪儿?
Where?
俄亥俄州的迪非恩斯
Defiance,Ohio.
今天有人要落网了
Someone's going down today.
我知道  圣母  我知道
I know,mami, I know.
莎拉... 我替你付了保释金了
Sara... I paid your bail.
你可以再晚一点来
You took your time.
我是州长
I'm the governor.
-我有很多事情要处理...  -省省吧
I do have things that... Go to hell,Dad.
你要是再这样
You keep this up,
就别想出去了
this may be the only place I'll be able to see you.
你不想知道我的解释吗?
Do you even want to hear my side of things?
不想知道  莎拉
Not particularly,Sara,no.
特别是现在我都不知道你算哪一边的
Especially when I have no idea whose "side" you're on.
但是我知道一件事
But I do know this.
总要有人要为福克斯河的事承担责任
Somebody is going to go down because of what happened at Fox River.
如果不是你的话
And it would be in both of our best interests
对我们两个人都好
if that someone was not you.
为了确保这个  我们必须采取些措施
And to ensure this,certain steps need to be taken.
首先
One:
你要去参加座谈会
you should go to a daily recovery meeting.
其次
Two:
你需要在审理前就去参加
you need to go before a judge
并且宣称无罪  还有...
and plead not guilty,and three,
爸爸  我不...
你必须告诉惩戒署
you need to tell the D.O.C.
你对他们越狱知之甚少
everything you know about how that prison was being run.
还有 珀尔狱长的事
And that Warden Pope,
因为斯科菲尔德帮他作私事
how he was granting favors to Scofield
他就给与斯科菲尔德特权
because Scofield helped him with his personal projects,
让他方便到达管制区域
thereby exposing him to certain restricted areas
从而使他有机会
where he may have been able
拿到医务室的钥匙
to obtain a key to the infirmary.
我不能那么做
I can't do that.
可以 你可以的  莎拉.
Oh,yes you can,Sara.
你可以  你必须这么做
You can do that and you will.
是我干的  爸爸
I did it,Dad.
我没有关门  不是别人
I left the door open,me and no one else.
那不是真的
That's not true.
是真的
Yes,it is.
那不是真的
That's not true.
莎拉...
Sara...
就照我说的去做
just do what you're told,
否则后果会很严重...
otherwise there will be consequences...
我们都会被影响到的
that will affect us all.
你知道我的意思吗?
Do you understand what I'm telling you?
明白
Yes,sir.
很好
Good.
再过一星期... 我会被任命为
新一任的美国副总统
the new Vice President of the United States.
他们会举办一个庆典  会邀请你
There will be a ceremony,you will be invited,
但是你却不能出席
but you will not attend.
再见  莎拉
-我们听点音乐吧  -不行
Let's put some music on. Don't.
我忘了
I forgot.
不能听电台
No radio.
这里太静了
Man,it's quiet out here.
里面一直都很吵
Inside,there was always noise,you know?
总有人喊叫  守卫们四处巡逻
Someone yelling,guards making rounds.
我都已经习惯了
I got used to it.
没错
You're right.
我们回去吧
We should go back.
那些纹身...
The tats...
不只是为了逃出来准备的  是吧?
they weren't just for getting out,were they?
越狱只是个开始
Breaking out was just the beginning.
现在才开始有点乐趣
Now,it gets a little more interesting.
看来我被绑到电椅上
Mm-hmm,'cause me being strapped to the electric chair
还不够有趣吗
wasn't interesting enough.
我是说 在里面会有些意外因素
All I'm saying is inside,we had the element of surprise.
但是没人知道我们的计划
No one knew what we were planning.
我有点担心那个男的
There's something about this guy--
电梯里的那个家伙
the one in the elevator.
他就像是...
It's like...
就像是他知道我们的目的地和想法
it's like he knows where we're  going,what we're thinking.
如果真的这样 一切都是时间问题了
If that's true,  it's just a matter of time
他会发现犹他的钱
before he finds out  about the money in Utah,
纹身的秘密 我们去墨西哥的方法
Bolshoi Booze,  our way into Mexico.
所有的一切
Everything.
你准备好了?
Are you ready for this?
打电话吧
Make the call.
语音信箱: 滴声后请留言
ELECTRONIC VOICE (on phone): Please leave a message after the beep.
是我
Hey,it's me.
我接到林肯了
I've got Linc.
我们在去那儿的路上
We're on our way there.
如果你因为什么原因不能去的话
If for some reason  you can't make it,
打这个电话找我  9-1-7-4-5-4...
call me back at 9-1-7-4-5...
我们刚刚从监听处拿到的
We just got this from surveillance.
你还记得斯科菲尔德在入狱前
You remember that voicemail Scofield prepaid
- 租用的那个语音信箱吗?  - 记得
for when he went off to prison? Yeah.
有人在里面留言了
Someone just left a message on it.
谁?
Who?
斯科菲尔德
Scofield.
好像是...
Something...
好像是关于一次会面  听起来他好像
something about a meeting,  it sounded like he was
在等某个人去听那个消息
waiting for someone else  to check the message
然后打回给他
and then call him back.
这是区号  那是手机号码
This prefix,that's a cell phone number.
只要手机开着...
As long as it's turned on...
我们就能追踪到他的确切位置
We can track exactly where he is.
不要做蠢事  不要做蠢事
Don't do anything stupid. Don't do anything stupid
不
No.
有事吗  警官
Is there a problem,officer?
知道为什么要你靠边停吗  先生
Do you know why I pulled you over today,sir?
超速
Speeding?
请出示你的驾照和车辆行驶证
Let me see your license and registration please?
是这样的  我
The thing is,I,uh...
我-我-我的钱包掉了
I-I-I lost my wallet.
行驶证也可以
Well,I guess your registration will have to do just fine then.
那么
So...
这是你的车吗 米勒太太
this is your car,Mrs. Miller?
米勒是我的妻子
Mrs. Miller's my wife.
我是米勒先生
I'm Mr. Miller.
好吧
Well
你的牌照过期了
your tags are expired.
我一会儿回来
I'll be right back.
他招了吗?
Did he sing?
就像竹筒倒豆子
Like a fat,sweaty bird.
嘿  亲爱的
Hey,sweet pea.
- 爸爸  - 过来
Daddy? Hey,come here.
看看你  都长这么大了
Oh,look at you. You're so big.
嘿  帮我一个忙
Hey,why don't you do me a favor
拿一只粉笔
and grab a piece of chalk
给爸爸在地上画一幅图
and draw Daddy a picture on the ground,okay?
你还好吗
So,how're you feeling,huh?
胃口还好吗
You keeping your appetite up?
还好吧
Sorta. I guess.
很好
That's good.
非常好
That's real good.
老天  看到你太好了  小宝贝
Oh,God,it's so good to see you,baby girl.
你知道爸爸现在的处境吗
Do you understand what Daddy is going through right now?
知道一点
Sorta.
但是学校的同学们都在谈论
But the kids at school have been sayin' stuff.
他们说什么了
Okay,what have they been saying?
他们说你上电视了是因为你是个坏人
They're saying you're on TV because you're a bad man.
那你怎么想呢
And what do you think?
我想 如果我在一个不能看到你的地方
I think if I were someplace and they wouldn't let me
我也会逃出去的
leave to see you,I wouldn't do what they said,either.
你知道吗
Well,you know what?
我们很快就能在一起了
We are gonna be together real soon.
我向你保证
I promise you.
但是你要帮爸爸个忙
But Daddy needs you to do him a favor.
我要你给妈妈带个口信  好吗
I need you to get a message to Mommy,okay?
好的
Okay.
我需要你去告诉她
Now I need you to tell her
如果她明白我告诉她的事
if she understood what I told her
而且愿意相信爸爸的话
and if she is willing to trust Daddy...
那么就在7点
that she needs to turn on the porch light
打开门廊的灯
at 7:00,okay?
你能记住吗
Can you remember that?
好样的
That's a good girl.
蒂蒂
Dede,
离围栏远一点  宝贝
stay away from the gate,honey.
爸爸要走了  好吗  小宝贝
Daddy gotta get going,okay sweet pea?
我爱你  爸爸
I love you,Daddy.
我也爱你  宝贝
I love you,too,baby.
那边
There.
不远了
It's not much further now.
好的  他们转出州际公路 目前向北开
Okay,they moved off
- 在38号公路上  - 请说
the Interstate,heading North on Route 38. Talk to me.
在哪儿
Where?
有一个巡警报告说
There's a patrolman who thinks he's has
他在宾州的拉特罗布截停了 苏克雷·费尔南多的车了
Fernando Sucre pulled over outside of Latrobe,Pennsylvania.
联系当地警局
Get in touch with the local dispatch.
告诉他们  我们要活捉这个人
Make it clear that we want this man in custody,
不是死尸
not in a body bag.
死人告诉不了我们他的朋友在哪
Dead men can't tell us where their friends are.
是的 明白了
Yeah,you got it.
应该是的 长得一样
It's gotta be,it looks just like him.
好的 我来处理
Yeah,I'll take care of it.
我会的
I will.
米勒先生...
Mr. Miller...
请你将手伸出车外
I'm gonna have to ask you to place your arms outside the vehicle please.
米勒先生 把手伸出来
Mr. Miller,I need to see some hands.
准备好了吗?
You ready?
好了
Yeah.
现在
Now.
就是这儿了
This is the one.
- 看到他了么?   - 没
Do you see him? Nope.
也许他没收到你的消息
Maybe he didn't get your message.
他们停下来了
They've stopped.
前面几英里处 那儿...
Couple miles up ahead. There's...
那儿没什么特别的啊 他们...
There's nothing up there. What...?
他们在等什么?
What are they waiting on?
或是等什么人?
Or who?
好的 很好 很好
All right,that's good,that's good,
哦 快点
Oh,come on.
快点!
Come on!
亮警灯
Go red.
快 警灯!
Now,go red!
还有一件事
Just one more thing.
你相信我么
Do you trust me?
当然
Of course.
有什么办法可以让猎人放弃追踪？
How do you throw the hunter off the scent?
毁掉猎物
Get rid of the prey.
记住 按下电台扫描后
Remember,once I hit scan,
在搜到103.7之前我们约有30秒的时间
we'll have about 30 seconds before it reaches 103.7.
然后就爆炸了？
And then she blows?
是的 准备好了没？
That's right. Ready?
是的
Yeah.
好了 我们闪
All right,let's go.
等等 音乐没有变过
Wait,The music is not changing.
等等 等等
wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
出问题了
Something's wrong.
怎么了
What happened?
我也不知道
I don't know.
一定要让它爆炸
But we're going to need the explosion.
他追来了
He's here.
这收音机大概卡了
The radio must have jammed.
我们必须手动调
We're going to have to set it off manually.
车随时会爆炸
The car could blow any second,Michael.
探员两分钟内就到了
Well,the feds are going to be here in about two minutes.
如果不能伪装成事故  我们就死定了
If it doesn't look like we're dead,we will be.
剪刀 石头 布
Rock,paper,scissors?
林肯?
Linc?
该我上了
It's my turn.
但愿能收到信号
Better pray for reception.
102.1和103.7之间有几个台？
How many stations between 102.1 and 103.7?
在这收台？
Way out here?
可能只有一个
Just one,probably.
玛丽克鲁兹在哪?
Where's Maricruz?
嘿 老兄听着
Hey. Hey,look,man...
不 不不 佩特你听着
No,no,no,Petey. You look.
我已经72个小时没睡了
I haven't slept in 72 hours,
我亲眼看着一个人的手被剁掉
I've seen a man's hand get chopped off,
我被人用枪指着 挖过坟墓
I've been... I've been shot at,dug up a grave,
偷了辆车 还扒了趟火车
stolen a car,jumped on a fricking a train,
求你告诉我 她在哪里
so please,just tell me where she is.
费尔南多 冷静下来
Hey,Fernando,slow down,man.
我正要告诉你 可你没听我说完就挂电话了
I was trying to tell you,but you hung up the phone,man.
婚礼在维加斯举行
The wedding-- it's in Vegas.
拉斯维加斯？
The city?
是的 几小时前 他们刚刚离开
Yeah,and they left a few hours ago.
等等 别 别冲动
Wait,no,no,no.
别这样 嘿 费尔南多
Come on,hey,come on. Fernando!
这可是经典老款...
It's pristine,man. It's just...
我保证会完好无损的还给你
Gonna be back to you in one piece,I promise.
- 我还没说要借给你呢 - 我也是别无选择
Can we go back to the partwhere I said no? I wish I had another choice.
你当然有路可选
You do have a choice.
这是1952年乌拉尔牌摩托车
Come on,man. It's a 1952 Ural motorbike,bro
如果你敢刮伤它
If you so much as scratch it...
我保证不会刮伤的
No scratches... I promise.
她是我生命中的最爱
She's the love of my life,bro.
我必须采取行动
I got to do something.
你是鬼上身了
You look like hell.
我刚从地狱回来
I've been through hell,
现在我要去拉斯维加斯
Now I just got to get to Vegas.
嗨 我是莎拉
Um,hi,I'm Sara,
我 嗯...
and I,uh...
嗯...
Um...
这些年来，我和不少有吸毒史的人共事过
over the years,I've worked with...more than a few people who had a history of addiction,
嗯...
and,uh...
我会告诉他们我可以理解
I would tell them that I could understand
他们的感受 因为我...
what they were going through,because I...
过去曾和他们一样
used to be just like them.
我也曾是个瘾君子
I used to be an addict,too.
我想...
And I think,uh...
我心里很清楚
I think that what's becoming clear to me
就是...
is that...
我能理解他们的原因是...
the reason I understood them is...
因为我和他们一样
because I am like them.
我从未真正戒掉毒瘾
I never used to be an addict.
大家好 我叫莎拉 我有毒瘾
Hi,my name is Sara,and I'm an addict.
你好 莎拉
Hi,Sara.
嗨 叫我兰斯 我也有毒瘾
Hi,my name's Lance,and I'm an addict.
兰斯 你好
Hi,Lance.
莎拉所讲的情况
I guess a lot of what Sara
引起了我的共鸣 我也有这样的问题
just said resonates with me in what I'm going through.
费尽心思实施越狱计划
Put in all that work,break out of prison,
却没想在这阴沟翻船
only to end up dead at the bottom of a ditch.
真可悲
Kind of sad really.
出事的是谁?
So,which one of them was it?
希尔斯
Shales.
希尔斯?
Shales?
斯科菲尔德
S-Scofield.
也许是斯科菲尔德
Might be Scofield.
或许还可以从残骸里找到他的哥哥
You're probably going to find his brother in there,too.
奥斯卡 希尔斯 是不是那个马宏追了很久的家伙
Oscar Shales is this guy Mahone tracked for a while.
讨人厌的杂碎
Nasty little bottom feeder.
你也知道这类人
You know the type.
依然在逃
He's still in the wind.
坏人抓不完啊
Can't get 'em all,right?
我们去犹他的路上清静了
We should have a pretty clear path to Utah now.
警察会把更多注意力放在其他人身上
They'll turn their attention to the other guys,
这段时间他们不会关注我们了
which means we'll be off their radar for a while.
他们很快就能拿到事故的尸检报告
They're going to get the lab results back from the accident,man.
到那时我们就已经到墨西哥了
We'll be in Mexico by that time.
如果交通工具能搞定的话
Provided the transport comes through.
宝贝 快点啊
Oh,come on,baby.
在"彩虹轩"
In the Rainbow Room.
还记得在那个美丽的地方吗?
o you remember  that beautiful spot
我们拍照的地方 窗边的那张照片
where we took that picture,  the one by the window?
我会在那儿等着
I am going to be waiting  in that spot
一周后的今天
one week from now.
她睡着了吧？
She sleeping okay?
是的
Yeah.
睡得很熟
Like a baby.
不错
Good.
你刚才说想告诉我些关于你丈夫的消息
So,you said you had some information you wanted to tell me about your husband?
看来我又欠你一个人情
Looks like I owe you another one.
没关系
It's okay.
嗯 一旦我们到了墨西哥
Well,uh,once we get to Mexico,
我会按我承诺的给你一万美元
I'll send you $10,000,like I promised.
外加3千算是补偿这车
Plus another three for the car.
你会去见那个医生么？
Are you meeting up with her,the doctor?
莎拉?
Sara?
我 嗯...
I,uh...
我 我不知道
I... I don't know.
我们该出发了
We should get moving.
下个小镇离这只有几英里
Next town is a few miles away.
好的
Yeah,that's fine.
我可以在那搭乘公车
I can catch a bus from there.
再次谢谢你
Thanks again,Nika.
我就知道这个娘们会帮我们找到他们
I knew the little whore would take us right to 'em.